Lloyd: So now that you've completed
session one of unit 2, it's time
to complete the relevant section
in the assessment booklet.
If you haven't already done so you can
download the assessment by clicking on
the assessment link on the final page of
session one, and then you should save that
in a suitable location on your computer.
Once you've done that you can then
open the assessment and, as you
can see, this is unit 2: Understand
Terminology Used in Coding.
You may also find it useful to download
and open the hints and tips, which will
assist you as you complete the assessment.
So as with unit one, there is some
assessment guidance at the top in
relation to the different command
verbs: describe, explain, identify,
list, define, state, outline.
So make sure that if that word is
included in the questions, such
as describe this, or explain that,
that you give a detailed answer.
So then scroll down to page
2, pop your name at the top.
And then we come to section one, which
is Understand Basic Computer Terminology.
The learning objectives are at the top,
the question in the assessment, and if
you need any assistance with this, you
can refer back to the course materials
and it indicates there whereabouts in
the course materials the information is.
So question one, and this is
a define question at first.
So define what the central processing
unit does within a computer and
explain how random access memory
is used within the computer.
So what is the central processing unit?
What is its purpose, what does it do?
And similarly for the
random access memory.
So this is RAM.
What is RAM?
What is the purpose of RAM and
how is it used within a computer?
And for question two, it's asking you
to use an example, define the term data.
So what is data?
So you can use an example from
the real world and then indicate
what data is in relation to that?
So what does data mean in
relation to computing and coding?
For question three, it's asking
you to list the key purpose of five
common data tapes used in coding.
And it's asking you...
it suggests there that you may
find it helpful to use examples.
So the first one's been given for
you, so the char character and
string's also entered in there.
So what is the purpose of that data type?
So what does it mean
when you utilise that?
So you need to list the data types
down on there, and what is the
key purpose of those data types?
And as it says, if you can give an
example of how it's used within coding
.
For question four, it's asking to
then identify how a computer stores
data and identify what other items or
devices are used to store backup data.
So where does the computer store
the data that is within it?
When you write something or you create a
document or whatever piece of information,
where does it store that data?
Again, not just within the computer or
the other places where that information
can be stored and used to backup data.
This could be removable devices so if you
mention some of those, and you can also
think of the elements within and cloud
computing that you can utilise there.
But also think historically there was some
certain ways of backing up data and that
are still used by some big organisations.
So you may want to consider those as well.
That is then section one.
So if you proofread through your
answers, do a spelling and grammar
check, just to confirm that everything
is accurate, when you're happy with
that, if you can then save that, and
then you can move on to session two.